# Schwyn Francis



schwynf@gmail.com



6309039996



linkedin.com/in/schwyn-francis-5a47a9199

## **Summary**

I currently work for Maricopa County Environmental Services in the Aquatic Health & Safety Department. My passion, education, and work experience have guided me to the field of web development. After self-teaching for about a year, I decided to take the next step in my career and I earned a Full Stack Web Development certificate from the University of Arizona. Main focus is MERN stack for server side development.

### Experience



#### Environmental Health Specialist

Maricopa County Environmental Services

Sep 2016 - Present (4 years 1 month +)

- # EHS inspector for the Aquatics Health & Safety Department
- # Regulate Maricopa County Environmental Health Code
- # Conduct public & semi-public swimming pool construction inspections and manage over 700 permits for routine compliance

# Laboratory Technician III

Doctor's Data, Inc.

Mar 2014 - Jun 2016 (2 years 4 months)

- # Conducted chemical analyses on body fluids, such as blood or urine, using LC/MS systems.
- # Worked with Agilent MassHunter Workstation, Orchard Harvest and Labvantage for instrument control, data acquisition, qualitative and quantitative data analysis, and reporting.
- # Provided support to the research and development staff in the Chromatography Department

#### Education



#### Illinois State University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Biology/Biological Sciences, General 2011 - 2013

#### **Licenses & Certifications**



Registered Environmental Health Specialist/Registered Sanitarian (REHSRS) - Arizona Department of Health Services

Issued Jan 2020 - Expires Dec 2020

Full Stack Web Development - University of Arizona

# Skills

JavaScript • jQuery • MySQL • MongoDB • indexedDB • Node.js • React.js • Express.js • GitHub • Heroku

# **Honors & Awards**



New Employee Of The Year - Maricopa County Environmental Services

Aug 2017 performance-driven